ユピーの一撃によって 討伐軍は分断された
I'll never betray them. Never. Can't See x If x You're Blind
大階段を完全に破壊し
Gon and his friends are led by Canary
なおも上って来ようとする者を 迎え撃つ構えのユピー
to the butler's office,
to attempt to meet with Killua.
その背後に
Aren't we there yet?
間一髪　２階に逃れた ナックルとメレオロン
We still have a while to go. How much walking do we have to do...
階下に
Honestly, I cannot believe this!
最も間近でユピーの攻撃に さらされたシュート
Kil was finally home! But the men allowed him to leave again!
マズい
And Father is just as guilty!
足をやられた
He released Kil without permission!
シュート！
Really, this always happens!
そして　モラウ
They never ask me before they act.
あとは任せたぞ。
Do you understand, Gotoh? Yes, ma'am.
ナックルの名は 呼ぶわけにはいかない
Th-This is a most critical time for Kil...
ん？
Why don't they understand?
ぐっ…　しゃらくせぇ！
That building?
ユピーの一撃で
Won't you get in trouble
for bringing us here?
瞬く間に切り裂かれた 「ディープパープル」だが そうしやすいよう モラウによって
They already know what I'm doing.
巧みに配置されたものだった
So I am prepared to take the consequences. If there's any trouble, I'll take responsibility.
ん？　あいつらは　おとりか！
I'm merely serving as a guide
for Killua-sama's friends.
あっ！
Killua-sama, we've been waiting for you.
バカが　逃がすか！
Canary is bringing Gon-sama here, along with his two friends.
己の武器をも おとりに使ったモラウには
Really? They should arrive shortly,
so please wait inside.
走る以外のすべは 残されていなかった
Okay.
ナックルは 呼ばれなくとも分かっていた
Let me know the second Gon gets here. Yes, sir. I shall notify you immediately.
チッ　地平線まで ぶっ飛ばす気合で殴ってんのに
Forgive me, Killua-sama.
くっ… １０秒が　永久くれぇ長ぇ
Hey, we finally made it.
能力発動時の時間経過に沿って 利息が加算されて行く
Welcome.
見失った！
Please forgive the rude reception.
おのれぇ!!
The lady of the house has
asked us to treat you
沸騰しかけたユピーを 冷静に戻したのは
as official guests.
増殖させた目が捉えた影
Is that better? Thanks.
右足を破壊されたシュートは
Then this is not the primary residence?
無意識のうちに 残った足で腕の上に立っていた
No, this place is for the butlers. Well, please make yourselves at home.
過去に　試したことすら なかったにもかかわらず
I appreciate the hospitality, but we've come to see Killua.
シュートは　これこそが 自分の奥義だと確信した
Can you take us to him at once?
加えて　右目をふさいだのにも
Killua-sama is on his way here.
明確な理由が あったわけではない
Really? Yes, so please wait a little longer.
ただ　当人は 追い込まれるほど
That's great news, Gon! Yeah!
力が　みなぎって来るのを この状況で楽しんでいた
Now, then... To simply sit and wait would be dull.
うぅ…！
A game?
シュートは飛んだのだ
Which hand holds the coin?
その すさまじいスピードと気迫は ユピーの全神経を　コンマ数秒
Marvelous. Then I shall try harder this time.
全ては
Well? Which hand?
他を生かすため
I'm not positive, but I'd guess the right.
シュート！　ナックル！
I have known Killua-sama his entire life. I dare say that I care for him
as though he were my own.
これが終わったら　まず
In all honesty, I must despise you for trying
to take him away.
うまい酒　浴びるほど飲んで 酔っぱらおうぜ！
Well? Which hand?
嫌がるお前らを 力いっぱい抱き締めるにゃあ
Answer.
それしか思い付かねえからよ
The left hand.
両陣営が舞い上げた 大量の粉塵は モラウが煙のオーラを 宮殿全体に広げて
His lady mother could barely speak...
戦況を把握するのに 好都合だった
She must be heartbroken,
having to watch him leave. I cannot forgive it.
モラウの標的は　玉座の間
By the time Killua-sama arrives,
a decision will be reached.
ユピーが 大階段を破壊した時…
I shall test you in my own way. You have no choice.
進路を変えていた
Canary!
東塔２階から 直接　玉座の間のある
Should you all be disqualified, I shall tell Killua-sama that you left.
中央塔３階へ跳ぶ算段である 突入と同時に
And that he will never see you again. Killua is...
地下へのエレベーターを目指した イカルゴを…
Silence! Your lives hang by a thread.
庭園で抜き去る 遺体を わが身のように操作できる能力
Now, answer my question.
複眼の使用が可能となった イカルゴは
Which hand?
「ドラゴンダイヴ」を 無傷で回避していた
I couldn't see it...
キルアが 視界の端に捉えたのは…
After three seconds have passed,
slit her throat. Okay. Wait! Left hand!
２匹の兵隊アリ
Me, too!
イカルゴの向かう先
One disqualified.
瞬間　キルアは走っていた
I can't see anything!
キルア！ 何でエレベーターの方向へ？
Man, how long do I have to wait?
何やってんだ？ 俺は一体…
Anyone around?
自身の行動に 衝撃を受けるのも当然である
What's going on?
個々の役割を守れと
Okay!
誰よりも厳しく周りに説いた 張本人なのだ
Now I can see. Give me your best!
キルアの思考は 完全に停止した
Which hand?
しかし
Who now holds the coin?
パニックに陥った頭とは 裏腹に… 彼の肉体は　合理的に働き
Hunter Vocabulary
オーラの消費を 最小限に抑えつつ…
Waiting Time
兵隊アリ２匹の戦闘能力と
The person right behind me.
見ていたのは イカルゴと　もう１匹
Killua! Oh! You're here, Gon! Along with... Kurapika?
クソ！
I had them participate in a little game. A game?
俺は… 何てことを！
It was nothing more than a poor joke. I apologize for any aggravation.
あっ。
Did you enjoy yourselves?
キルア…。
We butlers feel no emotional attachment to our employers.
貸しだぞ。
You're lying.
われに返って さまざまな感情が錯綜し
Gon-kun...
混乱しかけたキルアの頭の中を イカルゴの一声が払った
Well? Which hand? Isn't it your left hand?
２匹のアリが 音を立てて崩れた時
In this world, there are many
things that are wrong.
キルアは　もう前を向いていた
Please be careful. I am entrusting Killua-sama to you.
おかしい
Bye, Canary!
地下へのエレベーターが 配置されている廊下の両端には 使用人のための部屋があり
Took you long enough, Gon! Sorry about that. Let's make ourselves scarce
before more trouble comes.
現在は　兵隊アリが占有している
Yeah, he's used that trick on me before.
イカルゴが ２匹のアリの間を抜け
Once you know the secret,
it's so simple, it'll make you mad.
エレベーターに　たどり着くのと 時を同じくして…
Huh? Really? I'm assuming this was what he did.
あっ。 息を合わせたかのように
Which hand? It's your left hand, right?
両側の扉が開き始めた
Huh? How?
両の扉から現れたのは…
Hey, how did you do that? Gotoh held two coins. Huh? But he only had the one.
ヂートゥ！
And then he let us see him grab
the coin using his left hand.
ブロヴーダ！ ウェルフィンが フラッタを認め　身を隠したのは 違和感を嗅ぎとったからだ
But before he asked us
which hand held the coin, he raised both arms, and he slipped the first coin into his sleeve. That left the coin in his right hand.
早過ぎる
You got it. That really makes me mad.
兵隊アリ２匹が 敵を発見した際の警戒音
Well, I'm fairly certain he only used
the trick on the final turn.
そして　直後の断末
Gotoh hates cheating, even if it's just a game.
２匹を倒したらしき賊が 廊下を引き返すのと
That's even worse!
短過ぎる！
What? You're here on a tourist visa?
あれでは 確実に賊とフラッタは
Uh-huh. Didn't you pass the Hunter Exam?
廊下で すれ違っていなければならない
You could've just used your Hunter License.
なら　なぜ　２匹は殺され
It lets you stay in other countries
for as long as you want. That's what we said.
フラッタは　殺されなかった
I already decided.
フラッタは　賊側
I'm not using the license until I've
finished what I need to do.
つまり
What do you have to do?
裏切り！
The tag
いや…　レオルの指示か
I'll only take it back
何てザマだ
Until I do that, I won't use my Hunter License.
肝心な時に　そばにいないで
I can't go back to Whale Island, either. Hmm... So, where's Hisoka?
それで王直属の護衛軍？
Uh... Thought so...
王の所在すら分からず
I know where he is, Gon.
これで王直属の護衛軍？
Huh? Really? How? He told me.
否
So that's what he said...
護衛軍　失格！
No, this was after the orientation.
それだけのこと
But it's still related, right? I suppose so.
プフの忠誠心は
I've been itching to ask...
その強さ故の　もろさを併せ持つ
What did Hisoka say to you?
絶対的な理想が先にあり 修正が利かない
I have some information for you
regarding the spider.
フフフ…　アハハ…！
The Phantom Troupe? I do not recall mentioning the
Phantom Troupe to Hisoka.
アハハハハ…！ 元護衛軍　プフ
So either he overheard our conversation
during the first stage, or he heard of it from another.
さぁ　プフ　無能のプフ 愚か者め
The spider is the Phantom Troupe's symbol, so those familiar with the organization
refer to the Troupe as such.
護衛軍失格のプフよ 次に　どこへ行く？
I was interested in his information.
見当もつかない？
I see... So that's why you swallowed your pride
次に向かう場に 王がいなければ
and accepted Hisoka's surrender.
無能以下のクズですね
After the orientation, I asked him about it.
いや　無能のプフよ
I shall await you in Yorknew City,
on September 1st.
お前は認めたくないだけ
September 1st?
それは 自身のみならず　王にも及ぶ
Correct. From September 1st through September 10th, there will be an auction
絶対の王が　万が一にも
for unusual items, rare goods, and national treasures from around the world.
下せんな人間の身を案じ
The event attracts all manner of nasty folk
自ら下せんな人間の部屋に 足を運ぶなど
who come looking to satisfy their greed.
あっては　ならない!!
It's the biggest gathering of money in the world.
…のに 王は恐らく　そこにいる
So the Troupe will be there? They're a group of bandits. They would not let this chance escape.
私は　ここに来る前から 多分それに気付いていた
So on that day, Hisoka will be
somewhere in Yorknew City.
護衛軍失格なのは　王の居場所が 分からないからではなく
Okay. September 1st. Got it. Thanks.
さぁ　クズ以下の背信者　プフ
Then I shall depart now. Huh?
今からお前は　ただの虫けら！
We managed to see Killua again,
so I'm finished here.
自分に 何も期待してはいけない
I'll need money to participate in the auction.
故に　王にも 何も期待してはいけない！
So I shall search for a patron
to employ me as a Hunter.
ただ　ひたすら　王のため 王のため　王のため 王のため！　王のため！
Really... I guess I should go home, then. You, too?
王のため!!　王のため!! 王のため!!　王のため!! 王のため!!
I haven't given up my dream
of becoming a doctor. If I'm accepted to medical school, I can use this to pay the ridiculous fee.
むしろ 狂信にさえ近い　その感情は
I'll have to go back and start cramming. Uh-huh, good luck.
プフの正常な思考を妨げた
Until we meet again. Yes, that will be...
行こう　王の元へ
See ya.
よう。
Hey, what do you want to do? You have to ask? We train, obviously.
…って　無視かい！
Do you remember what you just said?
目もくれず 王んとこへってか…
Think you can punch Hisoka in
the face without training?
あいにくだったな 包囲させてもらったぜ。
You couldn't land a punch in ten years, let alone six months! Okay.
どうしたら
Here, I'll make it easy to understand. This is Hisoka. This is Hanzo.
出してもらえます？ いいや　出さねえな。 そうですか。
Uh-huh... If this is the gap between Hisoka
and Hanzo, in terms of strength, the gap between Hisoka and you
あれは　モラウの 「スモーキージェイル」
I don't know how to tell the
difference in strength between my opponent and myself. Stupid. It doesn't matter.
プフを王から分断するために 使うと言っていた技
I'm only estimating. You probably have a general idea.
塔の３階全体を 煙で覆っている以上
Once you have enough experience, your guess will become more accurate.
あそこに　王とピトーは　いない どこだ！
Besides, the stronger someone is, the better they are at hiding that strength. So you shouldn't rely on this method.
ゴンの闘志に　火が付いた
After bidding farewell to Kurapika and Leorio, with promises to meet again in Yorknew City, Gon and Killua now head to a new stage,
the Heavens Arena.